<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Mainroad</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Mainroad</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generate URL for Cloudwatch metrics from your code</title><link>/posts/aws-url-helper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/aws-url-helper/</guid><description>Get direct URL for AWS Cloudwatch metrics Introduction to the problem Last time, when I developed some integration with AWS, I got in trouble when I wanted to generate a direct URL to the Cloudwatch metrics. I could not find any working solution, so I decided to write my implementation.
I expect to get a URL to AWS Cloudwatch metrics for given metrics data.
What data do I have?
Statistic, Dimensions, MetricName, Namespace, Period You can find source code for the helper I implemented on my GitHub: AwsMetricUrlHelper.</description></item><item><title>Setup KVM on a physical server</title><link>/posts/setup-kvm-on-a-physical-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/setup-kvm-on-a-physical-server/</guid><description>Setup KVM on a physical server As part of my learning, I will try to explain to you how to install KVM on physical computer and server. That is the first stop on the road to install the OpenStack.
Assumptions: Do not use GUI* KVM cluster All VM stored on /mapper/red01(Raid5 matrix) Two networks: NAT and Bridge to physical interface As much automation as possible Note:
* Usually, I work with servers I have no real access.</description></item><item><title>[PL] What are exceptions</title><link>/posts/what-are-exceptions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/what-are-exceptions/</guid><description>Exceptions Wstęp Co, a w zasadzie kto skłonił mnie do napisania tego artykułu? Tak naprawdę to znajomi którzy kilkukrotnie pytali o wyjątki.
Co to jest tak naprawdę ten wyjątek? Dokumentacja PHP mówi:
An exception can be thrown, and caught (&amp;ldquo;catched&amp;rdquo;) within PHP. Code may be surrounded in a try block, to facilitate the catching of potential exceptions.
pl: &amp;ldquo;W PHP wyjątek może zostać rzucony i złapany. Kod może być objęty w blok try by ułatwić wychwytywanie potencjalnych sytuacji wyjatkowych(czyt.</description></item><item><title>[PL] Monitoring PHP + NGINX</title><link>/posts/php-and-nginx-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/php-and-nginx-monitoring/</guid><description>Wstęp Jeśli jeszcze nie wiesz co to jest php-fpm, jak działa to zapraszam do zapoznania się z innymi ciekawymi artykułami na ten temat, do których link znajdziesz na koncu
Tematem tego artykułu jest poprawa wydajności i eleminacja problemów z którymi naktnąłem się podczas wdrażania rozwiązania opartego o PHP-FPM i Nginx. Jeśli przeanalizujesz swój serwer zgodnie z tym jak zrobiłem to ja to będziesz miał gwarancję, że lepiej zrozumiesz jak działają rozwiązania które używasz i będziesz miał nad nimi lepszą kontrolę.</description></item></channel></rss>